====BTM字幕组制作====
本字幕仅供学习  请勿商业使用
翻译：零点 苍凌羽 小十 小吓
校对：毛毛         后期：小瞬
- 我们为什么要追它   - 紫红警报
- Why are we chasing it?   - It's mauve
它很危险 而且它会在30秒内到达伦敦中心
and dangerous and about 30 seconds from London.
打扰一下 我在找一样东西
Excuse me, there's this thing I need to find,
是从天而降的...
would've fallen from the sky...
Nancy 我在找的那样东西
Nancy, the thing I'm looking for,
你知道是什么 对吧
you know what I'm talking about, don't you?
啊
A-a-ah!
- 接住你啦 没事了   - 你好
- I've got you, you're fine.   - Hello.
你好
Hello.
我是Jack上校 一路上久仰大名
Jack Harkness, I've heard all about you on the way over.
现在是1941年 是伦敦闪电战的高峰期
It's 1941, the height of the London Blitz
有一样东西掉在了伦敦
and something else has fallen on London.
他说是一艘战舰
He said it was a warship,
他偷来的 然后把它停在了某处
he stole it, parked it somewhere out there,
炸弹会炸掉它
somewhere a bomb's going to
- 除非我们出价   -  这是个骗局
- fall on it unless we make him an offer.   - It's a con.
我在骗你们 这就是我 我是一个骗子
I was conning you, that's what I am, I'm a con man.
有东西在追你和那些孩子们
There's something chasing you and the other kids.
妈咪 妈咪
Mummy, mummy.
别让他碰到你
You mustn't let him touch you.
碰到了会怎么样
What happens if he touches me?
他会把你变成他那样的
It makes you like him.
好了 大家都出去
Right, everybody out, across the
穿过后花园 从篱笆下面钻出去 快 快走
back garden and under the fence. Now, go, move!
在哪儿都能看到他们
You'll find them everywhere,
每间病房 每张床上 有好几百个
in every bed in every ward, hundreds of them.
他们的伤都如出一辙
They've all got the same injuries,
手背上有伤痕
scarring on the back of the hand
防毒面具似乎和肉体熔在了一起
and the gas mask seems to be fused to the flesh.
死因是什么
What was the cause of death?
他们没有死
They're not dead!
你是我的妈咪吗
Are you my Mummy?
是我 我是Nancy
It's me Nancy!
别让他们碰到你们
Don't let 'em touch you.
要是被碰到了会怎样?
What happens if they touch us?
后果就在你们眼前
You're looking at it!
妈咪
Mummy!
回你的房间去
Go to your room!
我的认真的 我对你很生气很生气
I mean it. I'm very, very angry with you.
后果很严重
I'm very, very cross.
回 你 的 房 间 去
Go. . .To. . .Your. . .Room!
我很庆幸这句话有用
I'm really glad that worked.
要是这变成我的遗言的话 也太差劲了点
Those would have been terrible last words.
Jamie...
为什么他们都戴着防毒面具
Why are they all wearing gas masks?
他么没有戴
They're not.
那些面具是他们的血肉之躯
Those masks are flesh and bone.
你的骗局是怎样的
How was your con supposed to work?
很简单 真的
Simple enough, really.
搞些无害的太空垃圾残片
Find some harmless piece of space junk,
让最近的时间特工
let the nearest Time Agent
追踪到地球
track it back to Earth,
让他相信那价值很高 然后出个价
convince him it's valuable, and name a price.
当他付了一半的首付 啊噢
When he's put 50% up-front, oops,
一颗德国炸弹从天而降 永远得炸了它
a German bomb falls on it, destroys it forever.
他永远都不会看到自己买了什么
He never gets to see what he's paid for,
永远都不会知道自己买了一堆垃圾
never knows he's been had.
然后我用他给我的钱请他喝一杯
I buy him a drink with his own money
感叹下狗屎运
and we discuss dumb luck.
完美的 不露破绽的骗局
The perfect, self-cleaning con.
没错 很高明
Yeah. Perfect.
伦敦闪电战战最适合扫尾工作了
The London Blitz is great for self-cleaners.
庞培也很好 如果你想去旅游的话
Pompei is nice, if you want to make a vacation.
庞培：意大利古城 曾火山爆发被淹灭
但你最好在闹钟上设下火山日
But you gotta set your alarm for volcano day.
看来有人不喜欢我的话
Getting a hint of disapproval.
看看这间房间
Take a look around the room.
这就是你所谓的无害的太空垃圾残片的杰作
This is what your piece of harmless space junk did.
那是艘烧毁的医用运输船 里面什么都没有
It was a burnt-out medical transporter, it was empty.
Rose
Rose!
我们要走了吗
Are we getting out of here?
我们上楼去
We're going upstairs.
我甚至设置了飞行程序
I even programmed the flight computer so
它不会坠落到有生命体的地方
it wouldn't land on anything living.
我没有伤害任何人
I harmed no-one!
我不知道发生了什么 但相信我 与我无关
I don't know what's happening, but believe me, I had nothing to do with it.
告诉你吧
I'll tell you what's happening.
你忘记设你的闹钟了
You forgot to set your alarm clock.
- 今天是火山日   - 那是什么
- It's Volcano Day!   - What's that?
警报解除
The all clear.
但愿如此
I wish.
啊
Ah!
我以为你是Jamie
I thought you were Jamie.
- 妈妈 爸爸   - 熊孩子
- Mum, Dad!   - Ruddy kids!
放开我 放开我
Get off of me! Get your hands off me!
喂 你 进去 快进去
Oi, you, get in, get in!
把她弄进去 这个偷东西的小贼
Get her in there! She's nicked.
- Spock先生   - 博士
- Mr Spock?   - Doctor.
你有爆破工具吗
You got a blaster?
当然有
Sure.
你的太空垃圾坠落的那个晚上 有人受伤了
The night your space junk landed, someone was hurt.
这就是他被带来的地方
This is where they were taken.
发生了什么
What happened?
打开它 我们进去找答案
Let's find out. Get it open.
- 你的起子怎么了   - 没事
- What's wrong with your sonic screwdriver?   - Nothing.
音速爆破器 51世纪
Sonic blaster, 51st century.
Villengard武器工厂制造
Weapon factories of Villengard.
- 你去过那个工厂   - 以前去过
- You've been to the factories?   - Once.
这家工厂现在已经不在了 废弃了
They're gone now, destroyed.  Main reactor
主反应堆达到临界点 基本都蒸发了
went critical - vaporised the lot.
我说了 以前
Like I said, once.
那里现在是片香蕉林了
There's a banana grove there now.
我爱香蕉 香蕉可好了
I like bananas. Bananas are good.
爆破模式很酷
Nice blast pattern.
数码的
Digital.
正方形的枪   - 对
Squareness gun.   - Yeah.
我很喜欢
I like it.
你怎么看
What do you think?
有东西从这里逃出去了
Something got out of here.
对 然后呢
Yeah. And?
它很强大
Something powerful.
又很愤怒
Angry.
强大而且愤怒的
Powerful and angry.
一个孩子么
A child?
我想这解释了他为什么叫"妈咪"
I suppose this explains "Mummy"?
一个小孩怎么能做到这些
How could a child do this?
你知道你在哪儿吗
Do you know where you are?
你是我的妈咪吗
Are you my mummy?
你知道周围是什么吗
Are you aware of what's around you?
你能 看见 吗
Can you. . .See?
你是我的妈咪吗
Are you my mummy?
你想要什么 你知道...
What do you want? Do you know what. . . ?
我想要我的妈咪
I want my mummy!
你是我的妈咪吗 我要我的妈咪
Are you my mummy? I want my mummy.
你是我的妈咪吗
Are you my mummy?
妈咪 妈咪
Mummy? Mummy?'
博士 我听到过这个声音
Doctor, I've heard this voice before.
- 我也是   - 妈咪
- Me too.   - Mummy?
总是说 你是我的妈咪吗
Always, " Are you my mummy?"
就好像他不知道自己的妈妈是谁
Like he doesn't know.
妈咪
Mummy.
他怎么会不知道
Why doesn't he know?
你在那儿吗 妈咪
Are you there, Mummy?
妈咪
Mummy!
警察正在来的路上
The police are on their way.
这张桌上的食物都是我买的
I pay for the food on this table.
那些食物 都是我的血汗钱
The sweat on my brow, that food is.
我的血汗钱
The sweat on my brow!
您还要点什么呀
Anything else you'd like?
要不要我把整幢房子都给您啊
I've got a whole house here.
还有什么是您要的呢
Anything else you'd like to help yourself to?
对了
Yeah.
我要一把钢丝钳 谢谢
I'd like some wire-cutters, please.
可以剪断带刺铁丝网的那种
Something that can cut through barbed wire.
噢 还要一个手电筒
Oh, and a torch.
不要露出那副表情 Lloyd先生
Don't look like that, Mr Lloyd...
我知道你这儿工具多的是
I know you got plenty of tools in 'ere,
我注意你这幢楼好久了
I've been watching this house for ages.
我还想再看看你厨房里的橱柜
And I'd like another look round your kitchen cupboards.
第一次太匆忙了 我想看看有没有漏下什么
I was in an 'urry the first time, I wanna see if there's anything I missed.
这张桌上的食物...
The food on this table...
有很多 是不是 Lloyd先生
Is an awful lot of food, isn't it, Mr Lloyd?
比别人家的多了好多
A lot more than on anyone else's table.
半条街的人都以为你的太太
Half this street thinks your missus
和Haverstock先生 那个屠夫有染
must be messing about with Mr Haverstock, the butcher.
但她没有 是不是
But she's not, is she?
你才是出墙的那个
You are.
钢丝钳 手电筒
Wire-cutters. Torch.
食物
Food.
我离开前还想用一下你们家的卫生间 多谢
And I'd like to use your bathroom before I leave, please.
哦 瞧瞧
Oh, look!
都流汗了
There's the sweat on your brow!
妈咪 求你了 妈咪 妈咪
Mummy? Please, Mummy? Mummy?
博士?
Doctor?
- 你们能感觉到吗   - 感觉到什么
- Can you sense it?   - Sense what?
答案触手可得
Coming out of the walls.
- 你们感觉得到吗   - 妈咪
- Can you feel it?   - Mummy?
人类滑稽的小脑袋 你们怎么靠这个混的
Funny little human brains! How do you get around in those things?
他有压力的时候 就喜欢黑别的种族
When he's stressed, he likes to insult species.
Rose 我在思考
Rose, I'm thinking!
自己犯傻的时候
Cuts himself shaving, he does
也得先把别的种族说一顿
half an hour on life-forms he's cleverer than.
被炸后的废墟处 有一群流浪的孩子
There are these children. Living rough, round the bomb sites.
他们会在空袭间隙出来找吃的
They come out during air raids looking for food.
妈咪 求你了
Mummy, please?
假设在那个东西
Suppose they were there when this thing,
不管那是什么 坠落的时候 他们就在那儿
whatever it was, landed.
那是艘医用船 完全无害的
It was a med-ship, it was harmless!
你就矫情吧
You keep saying harmless.
假设其中一个孩子被感染了 变异了
Suppose one of them was affected, altered.
变异成什么了
Altered how?
我在这儿
I'm here!
它在害怕
It's afraid,
它怕极了 而且很强大
terribly afraid. And powerful. . .
它现在还没发现 但总有一天会的
it doesn't know it yet. But it will do.
它有天神的力量 但我刚刚我把它送回了房间
It's got the power of a god and I just sent it to its room!
- 博士   - 我在这儿哦
- Doctor...   - I'm here!
- 你看得见我吗   - 那是什么声音
- Can't you see me?   - What's that noise?
磁带放完了 大约30秒之前就放完了
End of the tape. It ran out about 30 seconds ago.
我在这里 你看到我了吗
I‘m here now, can't you see me?
我把它送回了房间
I sent it to its room.
这就是它的房间
This is its room!
你是我的妈咪吗
Are you my mummy?
- 妈咪   - 博士
- Mummy?   - Doctor?
好吧 听我口令
OK, on my signal,
- 开门准备...
- make for the door...
- 妈咪   - 冲啊
- Mummy?   - Now!
妈咪
Mummy?
快走 别扔下香蕉
Go, now, don't drop the banana!
- 为什么   - 富含钾离子
- Why not?   - Good source of potassium!
给我
Gimme that!
妈咪
Mummy?
数码回复 身手不错
Digital rewind. Nice switch.
Villengard香蕉林产的
It's from the groves of Villengard
我觉得还挺对等的
thought it was appropriate.
Villengard的中心真的有一片
There's really a banana grove in the
- 香蕉林吗 是你干的吗
- heart in Villengard? And you did that?
香蕉可好了
Bananas are good.
博士
Doctor!
快跑
Come on!
妈咪
Mummy!
它把我们堵在这里好抓我们
It's keeping us here till it can get at us!
是它在控制他们吗
It's controlling them?
它就是他们
It is them.
它是这间医院中每个生命体
It's every living thing in this hospital.
好吧 这玩意可以当成音速爆破器使
OK. This can function as a sonic blaster,
音速炮和一个三倍率的音速分解器使用
a sonic cannon and it's a triple-enfolded sonic disruptor.
博士 你有什么
Doc, what you got?
我有一个 呃 音速 算了 没什么
I've got a sonic, uh,. . . Never mind.
你说什么
What?
这好歹也是音速的 好啦 别讨论这个了
It's sonic, OK, let's leave it at that.
分解器 火炮 你的是什么
Disruptor, cannon, what?
我这个是音速的
It's sonic,
货真价实的音速 我全副武装
totally sonic, I am sonic-ed up!
- 一个音速的什么   - 起子
- A sonic what? - Screwdriver!
走下面吧
Going down!
博士 你还好吗
Doctor, are you OK?
你能提前打个招呼吗
Could've used a warning.
真感激不尽
Oh, the gratitude!
谁有个音速起子的
Who has a sonic screwdriver?
- 我   - 灯呢
- I do! - Lights?
谁看了音速起子之后会觉得
Who looks at a screwdriver and thinks,
哈 这实在是彻彻底底的音速武器啊
"Ooh-hoo this could be a little more sonic?"
这里肯定有个电灯开关
There's gotta be a light switch.
你从来不觉得长夜漫漫 你从来没装过柜子吗
Never had a long night? Never had a lot of cabinets to put up?
妈咪
Mummy!
- 到门口去   - 妈咪 妈咪 妈咪
- Door!   - Mummy? Mummy? Mummy?
- 该死   - 妈咪
- Damn it! - Mummy?
这些特殊功能实在太耗电池了
It's the special features, they drain the battery.
电池
The battery?!
这实在是太废柴了
It's so lame!
我原本打算再弄一个来的呢
I was going to send for another one.
但有人把工厂给炸了
But somebody's gotta blow up the factory.
我懂的   我见到他的第一天
I know. First day I met him,
他就把我的工作弄丢了
he blew my job up.
这就是他与人沟通的方式
That's how he communicates.
好了 那门应该能挡一会儿
OK, that door should hold it for a bit.
门   墙都挡不住他们
The door? The wall didn't stop it!
那他们总得先找到我们
It's got to find us first!
来吧 找点有用的东西
Come on. Assets!
呃 我有一根香蕉
Well, I've got a banana
必要的时候 你可以组装几个架子出来
and in a pinch you could put up some shelves.
窗户呢 有栏杆 跳下去绝对找死
Window? Barred. Sheer drop outside,
- 七层楼高   - 没有别的出口了
- seven storeys. - And no other exits.
所以 有用物品讨论就此结束了
Well, the assets conversation went in a flash,
是不是
didn't it?
那你是在哪儿把她救上来的
So where'd you pick this one up, then?
博士
Doctor!
她吊在一个拦截气球上
She was hanging from a barrage balloon,
我有一艘隐形飞船 而我从不放过任何机会
I had an invisible space ship. . . I never stood a chance.
好吧 首先 我们得离开这儿
OK! One. . . We've gotta get out of here.
但是 我们没办法离开这儿 我有漏了什么吗
Two. . .We can't get out of here. Have I missed anything?
是的
Yeah.
Jack刚才不见了
Jack just disappeared.
你们在想什么 都在这儿做什么
Thought as much. What are all of you doing 'ere?
每晚都要换地方 我说了多少遍了
Different house every night, I told ya!
我们以为你死了 或者跑掉了
We thought you were dead or you'd run off.
我没这么想 我知道你一定会回来找我们的
I didn't. I knew you'd come back for us.
我们在破烂堆里找到旧东西
Found that old thing in the junk.
他现在好像能写字了
Thinks he's can write now.
我在给我爸写信呢
Writing a letter to me dad.
你都不知道你爸现在在哪儿
You don't even know where your dad is.
还有你准备怎么把它寄出去
And how you gonna send it?
我不知道 把它封在一个信封里
I dunno, stick it in an envelope.
你连读和写都不行
You can't even read or write.
没有必要 我有台打字机
I don't need to, I've got a machine!
你能不能别再制造噪音了
Will you stop making that noise? !
对不起 Jim
I'm sorry, Jim.
你继续吧 如果你想的话就给你爸写封信吧
On you go, you write a letter to your dad if you want to.
我知道我们该转移了
I know we should've went somewhere else,
但是我们需要你 比如 为我们出谋划策
but we need you, see, for the thinking.
那我要是不在这儿呢
What if I wasn't 'ere?
要是有一天晚上我再也没回来呢
What if one night I didn't come back for ya?
战事胶着 人们都逃难去了
There's a war on, people go out.
不是所有人都能回得来的
They don't always come back.
这时有发生 那你要怎么做呢
It happens. What would you do then?
这原来是剪线钳
They're wire cutters.
我要你好好想想
I need you to think about that.
总得有人照看一切
Someone's gotta look after this lot.
为什么 你要去哪儿
Why? You going somewhere?
废墟
The bomb site.
在火车站旁边的那个
The one at the railway station.
- 为什么   - 那个孩子
- Why?   - The Child.
那就是他被杀的地方
That's where he was killed.
那就是一切开始的地方
That's where it all started.
我得弄清楚究竟是怎么回事
And I'm gonna find out how.
他会找上你的 接着他就会来找我们
He'll get you. And then he'll come for us.
- 他总是跟着我们   - 不是的
- He always comes for us! - No.
Ernie 不是的
Ernie, he doesn't.
他总是跟着我
He always comes after me.
有些事情我没有告诉你们
There are things I haven't told ya.
有些事情我难以启齿
Things I can't tell ya.
只要你们跟我在一起
As long as you're with me,
你们就有危险 即使现在 坐在这
you're in danger. Even right now,sitting here
你们因为我而身处险境
you're in danger because of me.
是你带着我们逢凶化吉
You're the one that keeps us safe.
你这么想吗 Ernie
You think so, Ernie?
那么告诉我
Then answer this.
Jim就坐在你旁边
Jim is sitting there right next to ya. . .
那是谁在打字
.So who's typing?
他来了吗
Is he coming?
Ernie 只要你们和我在一起
Ernie, as long as you're with me. . .
他就如影随形
he's always coming.
全是蔬菜 快吃吧
Plenty of greens. And chew your food!
好吧 他就这样凭空消失了
OK, so he vanished into thin air.
为什么做这种事情的总是帅哥
Why is it always the great-looking ones who do that?
我在努力不把你这话看成是对我的侮辱
I'm making an effort not to be insulted.
呃 我的意思是 男人
I mean. . . Men.
哦 谢谢 这样感觉好多了
OK, thanks, that really helped.
Rose 博士 能听见我说话吗
Rose? Doctor? Can you hear me?
我用了紧急心灵传输回到了船上
Back on my ship. . . Used the emergency teleport.
抱歉没办法带上你们
Sorry I couldn't take you,
它安全锁定了我的分子结构
it's security-keyed to my molecular structure.
我正在努力呢
I'm working on it.
你怎么跟我们说话的
How are you speaking to us?
Om-Com 有了它只要给我个通讯设备
Om-Com I can call anything
我就能和任何人说话
with a speaker grill.
多么惊人的巧合啊
Now there's a coincidence!
怎么了
What is?
那个孩子也可以做到   - 他能吗
The Child can Om-Com too. - It can?
只要带有通讯设备的东西
Anything with a speaker grill.
甚至连Tardis上的电话
Even the TARDIS phone.
什么 你的意思是那个孩子可以打电话给我们
What, you mean the Child can phone us?
我能听到你们说话哦
And I can hear you.
我来找你咯 来找你咯
Coming to find you. Coming to find you!
博士 你听见了吗
Doctor, can you hear that?
响亮清晰
Loud and clear.
我来试着屏蔽信号 至少我能做到这点
I'll try to block out the signal. Least I can do.
妈妈 我要来找你咯
'Coming to find you, Mummy.'
还记得这个吗 Rose
Remember this one, Rose?
我俩专属的歌
Our song.
Glenn Miller--Moonlight serende
你在做什么
What you doing?
试着与混凝土形成共振
Trying to set up a resonation
让栏杆松动
pattern in the concrete, loosen the bars.
你认为他不会回来了 是吗
You don't think he's coming back, do ya?
我用我的命跟你打赌
Wouldn't bet my life.
你为什么不相信他
Why don't you trust him?
为什么你那么相信他
Why do you?
他救了我的命 讨人喜欢 一定用了不少牙线
Saved my life. Bloke-wise, that's up there with flossing.
我相信他因为他有点像你
I trust him cos he's like you.
除了会约会和跳舞
Except with dating and dancing.
怎么了
What?
- 你刚才假设我   - 什么
- You just assume I'm. . . - What?
你真的认为我不会 跳舞
You just assume I don't. . .Dance.
什么 难道你是想告诉我 你
What? Are you telling me you do. . .
- 真的会跳舞   - 我都900岁了
- dance?   - 900 years old, me.
我一直四处旅行 我想你可以
I've been around. I think you can
假设我以前跳过舞
assume at some point I've danced.
- 就凭你   - 有问题吗
- You? ! - Problem?
你要是跳舞了 那宇宙还不炸翻天了
Doesn't the universe implode or something if you dance?
我不想自夸 但我还是有两下子的
Well, I've got the moves but I wouldn't wanna boast.
你有两下子
You've got the moves?
跳一段给我看看
Show me your moves!
Rose 我在尝试和混凝土建立共振呢
Rose, I'm, I'm trying to resonate concrete.
Jack会回来的 他会救我们出去的
Jack'll be back. He'll get us out.
来吧 世界不会因为博士跳了舞而终结的
So come on. The world doesn't end cos the Doctor dances.
- 拦截气球   - 你说什么
- Barrage balloon? - What?
你吊在一只拦截气球上
You were hanging from a barrage balloon.
哦 是啊
Oh, yeah.
就在你丢下我两分钟之后
About two minutes after you left me.
在伦敦几千英尺的高空上
Thousands of feet above London.
正值德国的空袭 而我的胸前挂着英国国旗
Middle of a German air raid, Union Jack all over my chest!
我和形形色色的人一起旅行过
I've travelled with a lot of people,
但你总能创造新的危险记录
but you're setting new records for jeopardy friendly.
这就是你跳的舞   我可是会好好记下的
Is this you dancing? Cos I've got notes.
吊在一根绳子上
Hanging from a rope.
悬在离地几千英尺的伦敦上空
Thousands of feet above London.
却没有被割伤 连淤青也没有
Not a cut, not a bruise.
是啊 杰克上校把我治好了
Yeah, I know. Captain Jack fixed me up.
我们现在改叫他Jack上校了啊
We're calling him Captain Jack now?
呃 他叫Jack 他是名上校
Well, his name's Jack, and he's a captain.
不是真的上校 Rose
He's not really a captain, Rose!
你知道我怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
我认为你在吃上校的醋
I think you're experiencing captain envy.
你的脚就接在你的腿上
You will find your feet at the end of your legs.
你也许可以试着挪个步子
You may care to move 'em.
即使他曾是个上校 那他现在也已经被解职了
If ever he was a captain he's been defrocked.
是吗 我怎么没听说过
Yeah? Shame I missed that.
实际上是我自己退的
Actually I quit.
不过没人拿走我的衣服
Nobody takes my frock.
大多数人在被心灵传输的时候会察觉到
Most people notice when they've been teleported.
你们总是那么有趣 对不起我来迟了
You guys are so sweet. Sorry about the delay.
我得把nav-com下线了
Had to take the nav-com
才能撤销心灵传输的安全协议
off-line to override the teleport security.
你要用10分钟撤销你自己的协议
You can spend ten minutes overriding your own protocols?
也许你该记住这是谁的船
Maybe you should remember whose ship it is!
是啊 她是多么的迷人
Oh, I do. She was gorgeous.
就像我告诉她的那样
Like I told her. . .
五分钟后回来
be back in five minutes.
这是艘Chula舰
This is a Chula ship.
是的 就像那艘医药用品运输舰
Yeah, just like that medical transporter.
不过只有这个是危险的
Only this one is dangerous.
它们就是把我手治好的东西
They're what fixed up my hands up.
Jack叫它们 呃
Jack called them, um. . .
Nanobots吗
Nanobots?
还是Nanogenes
Nanogenes?
是的,应该是Nangenes
Nanogenes, yeah.
亚原子机器人
Subatomic robots.
这里有几百万个
There's millions of them in here.
看见了吗 当我登陆控制台的时候
See? Burned my hand on the console
我的手烧伤了  现在全好了
when we landed.  All better now.
当船舱封闭时 他们就会被激活
They activate when the bulkhead's sealed,
检查你身体的受伤情况 任何伤口都能治愈
check you out for damage, fix any physical flaws.
带我们到坠落地去
Take us to the crash site.
我需要看看你的太空垃圾
I need to see your space junk.
等我登陆nav-com
Soon as I get the nav-com back on line.
你们请自便
Make yourselves comfortable.
继续你们刚才在做的事情
Carry on with whatever it was you were. . .Doing.
我们在谈论跳舞
We were talking about dancing.
不仅仅是在谈吧
It didn't look like talking.
也不像是跳舞啊
Didn't feel like dancing.
站住 别动
Halt! Don't move!
所以你曾是一位时间特工
So you used to be a Time Agent,
而现在你却想忽悠他们
and now you're trying to con 'em?
我也没那么坏
If it makes me sound any better,
因为我不是为了钱
it's not for the money.
那是为了什么
For what?
当我还在为他们干活的时候 一天早上我醒来
Woke up one morning when I was still working for them,
发现他们偷走了我两年的记忆
found they'd stolen two years of my memories.
我想要回我的记忆
I'd like them back.
他们偷走了你的记忆
They stole your memories?
整整两年
Two years of my life.
我都不知道自己做过什么
No idea what I did.
你那个朋友好像不相信我
Your friend over there doesn't
不过以我所见 他这么做是对的
trust me and for all I know, he's right not to.
好吧   我们该走了
OK! We're good to go!
坠落地点
The crash site?
不用起来了 你感觉好点没
As you were. You feeling any better?
只是碰了一下 长官
Just a touch, sir.
把她拷在Jenkins能看着的地方
Chain her up where Jenkins can keep an eye on her.
不  别把我留这儿  别和他一起
No! Not in here! Not with him.
如果不想待这儿就别闯进来啊
You shouldn't have broken in here if you didn't want to stay.
你不明白  别把我留他这儿
You don't understand! Not with him!
这里是限制区 小姐
This is a restricted area, Miss.
你可以在这儿稍微待一会儿
You can sit here for a bit,
我们过会要问你一些问题
we're going to have to ask you a few questions.
发现了这些 长官
Found these, sir.
很专业啊  有点儿专业过头了
Very professional. A little bit too professional.
看来并不是意外闯入
Didn't just drop in by accident,
- 对不对   - 我弟弟死在这儿了
- then, did you?  - My little brother died here.
我想知道到底是什么把他害死的
I wanted to find out what killed him.
带些人 检查一下围栏有没有其他洞口
Take the men, check the fence for any other breaches.
并且搜索整片区域 她可能不是一个人来的
And search the area, she may not have come here alone.
是 长官
Yes, sir!
拜托了 听着 你不能把我留在这儿
Please. Listen, you can't leave me here.
看好他 Jenkins
Watch her, Jenkins!
是 妈咪
Yes, Mummy.
- Jenkins   - 抱歉
- Jenkins?  - Sorry.
长官 我也不知道自己怎么了
Sir, I don't know what's the matter with me.
看啊 把我锁起来可以 可是别在这儿
Look, lock me up, fine, but not here.
求你了 哪里都行但别是这儿
Please, anywhere but here!
你不会有事的 小姐
You'll be all right, Miss,
我只是有点儿… 有点儿… 有点儿…
I'm just a little. . . Just a little. . .Just a little. . .
你到底什么毛病
What's the matter with you?
求你了  让我走
Please. Let me go.
- 为什么我要那么做   - 因为你
- Why would I do that?  - Cos you've
- 手背上有道伤疤   - 噢 没错
- got a scar on the back of your hand.  - Oh, yes,
有了又能怎么样
but what's that got to do with anything?
你觉得你生病了
And you feel like you're gonna be sick.
像有什么东西抵在你的喉咙上似的
Like something's forcing its way up your throat.
我了解的 因为我之前见过这种
I know because I've seen it before.
我到底怎么了
What's happening to me?
一分钟后你就不再是你了
In a minute you won't be you any more.
你甚至不会记得你是谁
You won't even remember you.
除非放我走 否则我也会变成那样  求你了
And unless you let me go, it's going to happen to me too. Please!
你到底在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你母亲叫什么名字
What's your mother's name?
Matilda
Matilda.
- 你结婚了吗   - 结了
- You got a wife?   - Yes.
妻子叫什么呢
Wife's name?
有孩子了没
You got kids?
你叫什么
What's your name?
拜托啊
Please.
放我走  你太迟了
Let me go. It's too late for you.
我很抱歉  但是快放我走啊
I'm sorry. But please let me go.
你要嗯嗯
What do you m. . . ?
么-么-妈-咪
M-m-m-mumm-y.
妈-咪
Mumme-e-e-e!
好了 就是这里
Well, there it is!
嘿 是Algy当班  肯定是要紧的事
Hey, they've got Algy on duty. Must be important.
我们得想办法过去
We've gotta get past.
转移士兵视线
Are the words "Distract
是我们的大体行动方针吗
the guard" Heading in my general direction?
我觉得那不是个好主意
I don't think that'd be such a good idea.
别担心 我能处理
Don't worry, I can handle it.
自从我来到小镇上后
I've got to know Algy quite well,
就挺了解Algy的了  相信我
since I've been in town. Trust me,
你不是他的菜  我来引开他
you're not his type. I'll distract him.
别等我了
Don't wait up!
淡定  这家伙是51世纪的
Relax! He's a 51st-century guy.
就跳舞来说他确实有够灵活
He's just a bit more flexible when it comes to dancing.
有多灵活
How flexible?
和他一起的时候 你俩可是穿越了半个星系
By his time, you lot are spread out across half the galaxy.
啥意思
Meaning?
样式那么多 时间又那么少
So many species, so little time.
那就是我们逃出来的时候要做的
That's what we do when we get out there?
那是我们的使命
That's our mission?
寻找新生和… 和…
We seek new life and. . .And. . .
跳舞
Dance!
嘿 老虎  怎么了这里
Hey, tiger. How's it hanging?
- 妈咪   - Algy 老伙计 是我
- Mummy?  - Algy, old sport, it's me.
妈咪
Mummy?!
是我 Jack
It's me, Jack!
Jack
Jack?
你是我的… 妈咪吗
Are you my. . . Mummy?
- 退后   - 你们 待那别动
- Stay back!  - You men, stay away!
这种病毒开始空气传播了 速度越来越快
The effect's becoming airborne, accelerating.
- 我们要怎么保障安全呢   - 没办法
- What's keeping us safe?  - Nothing.
- 啊 他们又来了   - 真走运
- Ah, here they come again.  - All we need!
你是不是说过炸弹会落在这儿
Didn't you say a bomb was gonna land here?
别管那个了
Never mind about that. If the
- 如果病毒现在是空气传播
- contaminant's airborne now,
- 那就只剩几小时了   - 会怎么样
- there's hours left.  - Till what?
会一无所有  永远的
Till nothing! Forever!
整个人类种族都不复存在
For the entire human race.
听到有人唱歌了么
And can anyone else hear singing?
宝宝的摇篮挂树梢
Rock-a-bye baby on the tree tops
风吹摇篮摇啊摇
When the wind blows the cradle will rock
枝断摇篮落树梢
When the bow breaks the cradle will fall
摇篮和宝宝一起掉
Down will come baby cradle and all. . .
宝宝的摇篮挂树梢
Rock-a-bye baby. . .On the tree tops
风吹摇篮摇啊摇
When the wind blows the cradle will rock.
瞧见没  就是个救护车
You see? Just an ambulance!
那是救护车
That's an ambulance?
很难解释 这是...
It's hard to explain, it's. . .
这是另一个世界的东西
it's from another world.
他们试图进入来着
They've been trying to get in.
当然了  他们认为
Of course they have. They think
他们得到了希特勒的秘密武器
they've got their hands on Hitler's secret weapon.
- 你在干啥   - 当你看到
- What are you doing?  - When you see this
这玩意是空的你就知道我啥都没干过了
thing is empty you'll know I had nothing to do with it.
噢
Oh!
- 上次可没这样   - 上次它可没摔过
- Didn't happen last time.  - It hadn't crashed last time.
这是个紧急协议
There'll be emergency protocols.
博士 那是啥
Doctor, what is that?
妈咪
Mummy.
博士
Doctor!
上校 守住那些门
Captain, secure those gates.
- 为啥   - 做就是了
- Why?  - Just do it!
Nancy 你是怎么进来的
Nancy, how did you get in here?
剪短铁丝网
Cut the wire.
带Rose过去  设置成2428-D
Show Rose. Setting 2428-D.
- 啥   - 修复那些铁丝网  快去
- What?  - Re-attaches barbed wire. Go!
你是谁  你们都是谁啊
Who are you? Who are any of you?
说了你一定不信
Never believe me if I told ya.
你刚刚还跟我说那是从另一世界来的救护车
You just told me that was an ambulance from another world.
带着防毒面具的人到处乱跑
People are running round with gas mask
还叫着他们妈咪 天上全是炸弹
heads calling for their mummies, the sky's full of bombs.
告诉我吧 你觉得我还有什么不会相信呢
Tell me, do you think there's anything left I couldn't believe?
我们是来自未来的时间旅行者
We're time travellers from the future.
疯了 你们都疯了
Mad, you are!
我们有一个时间机器 我是说真的
We have a time travel machine. Seriously.
不会的
It's not that.
好吧 你们有个时间机器 这我信
All right, you got a time travel machine, I'll believe ya.
我会相信任何东西  但未来是什么啊
Believe anything, me. .But what future?
Nancy 这不是终点
Nancy, this isn't the end.
我知道现在的局面
I know how it looks, it's not the
但这不是世界末日还是别的什么的
end of the world or anything.
你怎么能那么说呢
How can you say that?
- 看看这儿   - 听我说
- Look at it.  - Listen to me.
我在这个城市出生
I was born in this city.
我来自这里 差不多50年之后
I'm from here. In like 50 years time.
- 来自这儿   - 我是伦敦人
- From here?  - I'm a Londoner.
就在你的未来
From your future.
可是... 可是你不是...
But. . .But you're not. . .
什么
What?
德国人
German.
Nancy 德国人不会来这儿 他们赢不了
Nancy, the Germans don't come here. They don't win.
不要告诉任何人我给你说过
Don't tell anyone I told you so.
可是你知道么  你们胜利了
But you know what? You win.
我们胜利了
We win?
来吧
Come on!
这是空的  你看啊
It's empty. Look at it.
你还指望一个Chula医疗运输机里能有啥
What do you expect in a Chula Medical Transporter?
绷带  止咳片
Bandages? Cough drops?
- Rose   - 我不知道
- Rose?  - I dunno.
不 你知道的
Yes, you do.
nanogenes
Nanogenes!
这可不是空的 上校
It wasn't empty, Captain.
这有足够重建一个种族的nanogenes
There was enough nanogenes in there to rebuild a species.
- 噢 老天   - 你可算明白了 是不
- Oh, God.  - Getting it now, are we?
飞船坠毁的时候
When the ship crashes,
这些nanogenes就溜走了
the nanogenes escape.
多的数之不尽
Billions upon billions of them.
准备着去修复全世界的割伤和擦伤
Ready to fix all the cuts and bruises in the whole world.
但他们最先找到的是一个死去的孩子
But what they find first is a dead child.
大概是前一晚被害的
Probably killed earlier that night.
并且带着一个防毒面具
And wearing a gas mask.
然后他们把他复活了
And they brought him back to life?
- 他们能做到的   - 什么是生命啊
- They can do that?  - What's life?
生命很简单  只不过是一件奇怪的事
Life's easy. A quirk of matter.
就是保持肉体新鲜的自然方法
Nature's way of keeping meat fresh.
对nanogenes来说没什么
Nothing to a nanogene.
可还有一个问题
One problem though.
这些nanogenes
These nanogenes,
他们不像你飞船上的那些
they're not like the ones on your ship.
这些之前可从来没有见过人类
This lot have never seen a human being before.
根本不知道一个人类的正常形态是怎样的
Don't know what a human being's supposed to look like.
他们所了解的全部都是来自这样一个小男孩
All they've got to go on is one little body,
而周围像他一样的人可不多
and there's not a lot left.
不过他们就这样继续发展
But they carry right on, they do
他们按照计划进行着 - 他们不断修复
what they're programmed to do - they patch it up.
说不清什么是防毒面具
Can't tell what's gas
什么是头骨 但他们尽他们所能的去做
mask and what's skull but they do their best.
做完一切他们就撤了 远走高飞 工作完成了
Then off they fly, off they go, work to be done!
你也看见了
Cos you see, now they
现在他们自认为知道了人类是个什么样子
think they know what people should look like.
所以是时候把剩下的人都修复成那样
And it's time to fix all the rest.
并且不会停止
And they won't ever stop.
他们永远都不会停止
They won't ever, ever stop.
整个人类种族都会被拆卸
The entire human race is gonna be
然后重建成那个作为蓝本的恐怖孩子的样子
torn down and rebuilt in the form of one terrified child,
不停地寻找他们的母亲
looking for its mother.
并且这世上什么都阻止不了它
And nothing in the world can stop it!
我又不知道会这样
I didn't know.
妈咪 妈咪 妈咪 妈咪
Mummy, Mummy, Mummy, Mummy.
Rose
Rose!
这玩意把面具人都集中到这里来了
It's bringing the gas-mask people here.
飞船认为它被袭击了  所以呼叫了军队
The ship thinks it's under attack. It's calling the troops.
这是标准协议
Standard protocol.
但戴面具的人又不是军队
But the gas-mask people aren't troops!
现在他们是了  这是战时救护军
They are now. This is a battlefield ambulance.
纳米基因治疗剂不会只治好你
The nanogenes don't just fix you up, they
他们会把你送上前线  武装你 编码你
get you ready for the front line. Equip you, programme you. . .
这就是为什么那孩子这么厉害
That's why the Child's so strong?
为什么他能那样打电话
Why it could do that phoning thing?
他是一个全部武装的Chula战士 是的
It's a fully-equipped Chula Warrior, yes.
所有的武器技术都在一个四岁大的孩子手里
All that weapons tech in the hands
寻找着他的妈咪
of an hysterical four-year-old, looking for his Mummy
现在组成了一支军队
and now there's an army of them.
妈妈
Mummy!
他们怎么没有攻击行为
Why don't they attack?
听话的士兵们
Good little soldiers.
等着首领的指示呢
Waiting for their commander.
那个小男孩
The Child!
- Jamie   - 什么
- Jamie.   - What?
不是那个孩子 是Jamie
Not the Child, Jamie.
离炸弹爆炸还有多久
So how long until the bomb falls?
- 任何时候   - 有什么事 上尉
- Any second.   - What's the matter, Captain?
你是不是离火山太近了
Bit close to the volcano for you?
- 他只是个小孩子   - 我知道
- He's just a little boy.   - I know.
他只是一个想找妈妈的小孩子
He's just a little boy who wants his Mummy.
我知道
I know.
没有什么孩子
There isn't a little boy born who
是可以毁灭世界来拯救他母亲的
wouldn't tear the world apart to save his Mummy.
但是这个孩子可以
And this little boy can.
那我们要做些什么
So what are we gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
是我的错
It's my fault.
- 别这么说   - 就是的 都是我的错
- No.   - It is. It's all my fault.
- 怎么会是你的...   - 妈妈
- How can it be your. . . ?   - Mummy!
Nancy 你多大了
Nancy, what age are you?
20或者21 比你看起来要大 是吧
20, 21? Older than you look, yes?
博士 那个炸弹...我们时间不多了
Doctor, that bomb. . . We've got seconds!
你用心灵运输送走我们
You can teleport us out.
没法送你们 nav-com重新联网了
Not you guys. The nav-com's back on line,
要很久才能越过协议
gonna take too long to override the protocols.
是火山日了
So it's Volcano Day.
- 做你该做的去   - Jack
- Do what you've got to do!   - Jack?
五年前你多大 15或者16吗
How old were you five years ago, 15? 16?
反正够生孩子了吧
Old enough to give birth anyway.
他不是你弟弟 对吧
He's not your brother, is he?
在1941年一个单身少年妈妈
Teenage single mother in 1941.
你只有掩盖事实 你撒谎了
So you hid. You lied.
甚至对你的孩子撒谎
You even lied to him.
你是我妈妈吗
Are you my mummy?
他会不断地问的 Nancy
He's gonna keep asking, Nancy.
他不会停止的  告诉他吧
He's never gonna stop. Tell him.
Nancy 人类的未来就掌握在你手中了
Nancy, the future of the human race is in your hands.
相信我 去告诉他
Trust me and tell him.
你是我妈咪吗
Are you my mummy?
是的 是的 我是你妈咪
Yes. Yes, I am your mummy.
- 妈咪   - 我在这儿
- Mummy?   - I'm here!
你是我妈咪吗
Are you my mummy?
我就在这儿
I'm here.
- 你是我妈咪吗   - 是的
- Are you my mummy?   - Yes.
你是我妈咪吗
Are you my mummy?
他不懂的 他去世的时候还太小
He doesn't understand, there's not enough of him left.
我是你妈咪
I am your mummy.
我一直都是你妈咪
I will always be your mummy.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
真的很对不起
I am so, so sorry.
这是怎么了
What's happening?
- 博士 这是在改变她的...
- Doctor, it's changing her,
-我们要去...   - 嘘
-we've...  - ssh!
一定要成功
Come on, please!
聪明nanogenes你一定行的
Come on, you clever little nanogenes.
快认出它来啊
Figure it out!
她就是那个妈妈
The mother, she's the mother.
信息足够多了
It's gotta be enough information.
- 快辨认出就行了   - 发生了什么
- Figure it out!   - What's happening?!
看见没
See?
辨认相同的DNA
Recognising the same DNA!
来吧
Oh, come on!
快让我见证一下这一刻
Gimme a day like this!
来吧
Gimme this one!
哈哈哈哈
Ha-ha, ha-ha!
欢迎回来
Welcome back!
20年后的流行音乐你一定会喜欢的
20 years to pop music, you're gonna love it.
这是怎么回事
What happened?
拿龙更滋可以识别高级信息
The nanogenes recognised the superior information.
父母的DNA 他们没有改变你
The parent DNA. They didn't change you,
因为你改变了他们 哈哈
because you changed them. Ha-ha!
- 世上只有妈妈好   - Jamie
- Mother knows best. Jamie. . .
博士 炸弹...
Doctor, that bomb. . .
- 我来搞定  - 怎么弄   - 意念
- Taken care of it.  - How?   - Psychology.
- 博士   - 好样的
- Doctor!   - Good lad.
- 炸弹已经要开始爆炸了
- The bomb's already commenced detonation.
我把它停滞住了 不过这管不了多久
I've put it in stasis, but it won't last long!
计划有变 不需要炸弹了
Change of plan! Don't need the bomb.
你可以清除掉它吗 越安全越好
Can you get rid of it, safely as you can?
- Rose   - 怎么了
- Rose?   - Yeah?
再见
Goodbye!
还有...我挺喜欢这件T恤的
By the way. . .Loved the t-shirt!
- 这是在干什么   - 软件补丁
- What are you doing?   - Software patch.
将会发送新数据
Gonna email the upgrade.
你想跳舞是吧 Rose 我就给你看跳舞
You want moves, Rose. I'll give you moves!
所有人都活着 Rose
Everybody lives, Rose.
就是现在
Just this once!
所有人都活着
Everybody lives!
从未离开过自己的病人的Constantine医生
Dr Constantine, who never left his patients.
你的腿回来了 永远的医生
Back on your feet, constant doctor.
世界需要您这样的人
World doesn't want to get by without you just yet
我暂时也没啥不满足的了
and I don't blame it one bit.
这些都是你的病人  都痊愈了
These are your patients. All better now.
是啊 是啊 看起来真的好多了呢
Yes. Yes, so it seems.
他们也看起来
They also seem to be
像站在一个废弃的地铁站
standing around in a disused railway station.
是怎么一回事
Is there any particular reason for that?
是的 时光倒转嘛
Yeah, well, cutbacks.
不管他们以前有什么病
Whatever was wrong with them in the
现在你会发现他们都已经痊愈了
past you're probably gonna find that they're cured.
就告诉他们你是一个多么高明的医生就好了
Just tell 'em what a great doctor you are,
这没什么的 好吗
don't make a big thing of it. OK?
Constantine医生
Dr Constantine.
Harcourt夫人 您看起来好多了啊
Mrs Harcourt, how much better you're looking!
我的腿长回来了
My leg's grown back!
我来医院看的时候 可只有一条腿呢
When I come to the hospital, I had one leg!
现在正在战乱 可能是您记错了吧
Well, there is a war on, is it possible you miscounted?
是的 你们有许多要做的
Right, you lot, lots to do.
战胜德国 拯救世界 别忘了完善福利制度
Beat the Germans, save the world, don't forget the welfare state!
所有人都走了之后把这里自动毁灭了
Setting this to self destruct soon as everybody's clear.
历史上记载这里是有一个爆炸的
History says there was an explosion here.
我去跟谁争历史上的事
Who am I to argue with history?
谁先占上是谁的
Usually the first in line.
nanogenes会把混乱清理好
The nanogenes will clean up their mess and switch themselves off
因为我已经安排好了  Nancy
cos I just told them to. Nancy and
和Jamie会去找Constantine医生求助
Jamie will go to Dr Constantine for help. . .Ditto.
总之 一切都没问题了 太好了
All in all, all things considered, fantastic!
瞧瞧你这样子 笑得像
Look at you, beaming like
你就是圣诞老人一样
you're Father Christmas!
谁说不是呢
Who says I'm not?
你12岁的时候还送了你一辆红色自行车呢
Red bicycle when you were 12.
什么
What?
现在所有人都恢复了 Rose
Ands everybody lives, Rose.
所有人啊 我真想天天都过这样的日子
Everybody lives. I need more days like this!
博士
Doctor. . .
继续问 问我什么都行 我现在满腔热情
Go on, ask me anything. I'm on fire.
那Jack呢  他为什么会说再见
What about Jack? .Why did he say goodbye?
电脑
OK, computer. . .
我们还能把炸弹锁定多久
how long can we keep the bomb in stasis?
锁定削弱90%
Stasis decaying at 90% cycle.
3分钟后到达目的地
Detonation in three minutes.
我们可以投弃它吗
Can we jettison it?
任何试图投弃的操作都会加速爆炸
Any attempt to jettison the device will precipitate detonation.
百分之百的可能
100% probability.
那我们可以把它固定在逃生舱上呢
We could stick it in an escape pod?
甲板上没有逃生舱
There is no escape pod on board.
看看有没有裂缝 我去找逃生舱
OK, see the flaw in that. I'll get in the escape pod.
甲板上没有逃生舱
There is no escape pod on board.
所以地方都确认了吗
Did you check everywhere?
- 确定  - 船舱下呢   - 确定
- Affirmative. - UNDER THE SINK? - Affirmative.
算了
Ok.
我死亡的概率有多大
Out of 100, exactly how dead am I?
Jack Harkness于两分钟内死亡
Termination of Captain Jack
概率 百分之百
Harkness in under two minutes, 100% probability.'
谢了
Lovely, thanks.
知道概率也好
Good to know the numbers.
- 不客气   - 那就
- You're welcome. -OK, then!
- 执行紧急协议417吧   - 确定
- Think we'd better initiate emergency protocol 417. - Affirmative.
这苦艾酒还有点多呢
Ooh, a little too much vermouth.
看看我是不是又来这了
See if I come here again.
真是有趣
Funny thing. . .
上次我被判死刑时
Last time I was sentenced to death,
我早餐还订了4杯特浓伏特加呢
I ordered four hyper-vodkas for my breakfast.
喝完之后就神志不清
All a bit of a blur after that.
醒来了之后看到我的两个死刑执行人在我床边
Woke up in bed with both my executioners.
唔 真是有爱的一对儿啊
Mmm, lovely couple.
他俩还有联系呢
They stayed in touch.
其他的就不说了
Can't say that about most executioners.
不管怎么样
Anyway. . .
多亏你了 电脑
Thanks for everything, computer. . .
很不错了
it's been great.
来啊 快点来
Well, hurry up, then!
好的 转个身
OK. . .And turn.
好的 试着在把我转一圈
OK, try and spin me again.
但是这次不要把我的手扭到我的背后
But this time don't get my arm up my back!
不要再采用这样的姿势
No extra points for a half-nelson.
我确定我曾经知道这些东西 请你关上门好吗
I'm sure I used to know this stuff. Close the door, will you?
你的船都快爆炸了 会有气流的
Your ship's about to blow up, there's gonna be a draft.
欢迎来到TARDIS
Welcome to the TARDIS.
里面宽敞多了 你最好表现好点
Much bigger on the inside. You'd better be.
我想博士想试着说的是 你也许可以加入我们
I think what the Doctor is trying to say is. . .You may cut in.
Rose
Rose!
我刚想起来了
I've just remembered!
什么
What?
我能跳舞 我能跳舞
I can dance! I can dance!
实际上 博士
Actually, Doctor,
我觉得Jake可能会喜欢这样的舞
I thought Jack might like this dance.
我确定他一定会喜欢的 Rose
I'm sure he would, Rose,
我十分确定 但是和谁跳呢
I'm absolutely certain. . .But who with?
哇哦 哇哦
Whoo! . .Ooh!
我过的很不错啊
And I was having such a nice day.
根据情报
According to intelligence,
目标是Slitheen家族的最后一个生还者
the target is the last surviving member of the Slitheen family,
来自Rexicoricophalvitorius星球的犯罪团伙
a criminal sect from the planet Rexicoricophalvitorius,
他们会裹上人的皮肤 以此乔装成人类
masquerading as a human being zipped inside a skin-suit.
就在Cardiff城中心地带的核电站
This nuclear power station right
可以为大家提供工作
in the heart of Cardiff city will bring jobs for all.
正好发生在裂缝的正上方
And it just so happens to be right on top of the rift.
如果这个核电站融化的话
If this power station went
整个星球将大乱
into melt-down the entire planet would go schloop.
继续 然后 赶快跑
Ah, Go on, then, run!
是裂缝 这个裂缝即将打开
It's the rift, the rift's opening.
整个城市都即将毁灭
The whole city's gonna disappear!
时空要被撕裂了  这个星球即将被打开了
Time and space are ripping apart. It's gonna rip open the planet!